What if everything you learned about
Rome's fall was wrong?
Today, we uncover the truth that
historians have debated for centuries.
The Roman Empire didn't fall in a day.
For over three hundred years, it slowly
crumbled under the weight of its own
ambitions.
Economic collapse, military overextension,
and political corruption all played their
part.
Let's start with the economy.
By the third century, Rome was bleeding
money.
The cost of maintaining a vast army
drained the treasury.
Emperors debased the currency, flooding
the market with coins that contained less
and less silver.
Then came the military crisis.
Rome's legions, once the most feared
fighting force in the world, were
stretched thin across thousands of miles
of frontier.
Barbarian raids increased.
The empire struggled to respond.
Political chaos made everything worse.
In just fifty years, Rome had over fifty
emperors.
Most were assassinated.
Stability became impossible.
The Senate lost its authority, and the
rule of law gave way to the rule of the
sword.
And yet, the Eastern Roman Empire survived
for another thousand years.
This tells us that Rome's fall wasn't
inevitable.
It was the result of specific choices made
by specific people in specific
circumstances.
That's the lesson history teaches us.
Great civilizations don't fall because of
fate.
They fall because of decisions.
And that's a lesson we would do well to
remember today.
If you found this video valuable, hit the
like button and subscribe for more history
that challenges what you think you know.
What do you think was Rome's biggest
mistake?
Let us know in the comments.